Previously on
The Big Bang Theory...
여자애가 하나 있었어
Well, there was this girl.
무슨 짓을 한거야?
What did you do?
아무것도 안했어
Nothing.
그냥 키스 정도였어
Really, it was just kissing.
(sighs)
알았어
All right.
여전히 결혼은 하는거지?
So, we're still
getting married?
그래
Yes.
우리가 서로 사랑하기 때문에 하는거지?
Because we love each other.
그래
Yes.
우리 인생에서 가장 행복한 날이 될거야
And it's the happiest day
of our life.
어림도 없지
(chuckles)
Don't push it.
잠깐 우리의 상황을 고려해 볼
I need some time
to take a step back
시간이 필요한 것 같아
and reevaluate our situation.
Oh.
잘 있어, 쉘든
Bye, Sheldon.
골룸아
Well, Gollum...
넌 반지에 관해선 전문가잖니
...you're an expert on rings.
이제 이걸 어째야할까?
What do I do with this one?
어떤 패키지로 할까?
So, what package
are you thinking?
이건 음악하고 꽃들이 있는거구
Mm, this one comes with
music and flowers.
심지어 인터넷에서 중계도 해줄 수 있네
Oh, they even stream the whole
thing live on the Internet.
왜 중계를 하려구?
Why would we want that?
왜냐하면 저 밖에는 많은 매력적인 금발 미녀들은
'Cause there's a lot
of gorgeous blondes out there
자기들이 키도 작고 근시를 가진 과학자들이랑
결혼할 수 있으리라곤 생각하지 못하거든
who don't believe they can land
a short, nearsighted scientist.
걔네한테 희망을 심어주자구
Let's give them hope.
어쨌든 인터넷에 올리자
Whatever. Put us
on the Internet.
예전부터 결혼식에 댓글이 달려보고 싶었거든
I've always wanted a wedding
with a comment section.
마음이 내키지 않으면 다음에 해도 돼
I-If you're not into this,
we can do it another time.
아니야, 나도 하고 싶어
No. No, I want to.
오랜동안 끌어왔었잖아
Look, we've put this
off long enough.
해치워버리자
Let's do it.
Aw.
That's exactly what you said the
first time we slept together.
우리가 처음 잤을 때 했던 말이네
That's exactly what you said the
first time we slept together.
(ringtone playing)
잠깐만
Oh, excuse me.
쉘든이네
Sheldon.
여보세요
Hey.
Leonard, have you
gotten married yet?
레너드, 아직 결혼한거 아니지?
Leonard, have you
gotten married yet?
응, 무슨일인데?
No. Why?
Good. Don't do it!
Why not?
-잘됐네 하면 안돼!
-왜 안되는데?
Good. Don't do it!
Why not?
새로히 아주 중요한 정보가 생겼거든
Some important new information
has come to light.
여자들은 최악이야
Women are the worst.
종이에 베인 상처가 최악인줄 알았는데 아니었어
I thought it was paper cuts,
but I was wrong.
그 어떤 종이도 이렇게 깊게 날 벤 적이 없으니깐
No piece of paper
ever cut me this deep.
무슨 일인데?
What happened now?
에이미가 우리의 관계를 끝내버렸어
Amy has ended our relationship.
Oh, no. Seriously?
이런
진짜로?
Oh, no. Seriously?
왜 그래?
What's going on?
에이미랑 쉘든이 헤어졌대
Amy broke up with Sheldon.
에이미가 그랬다고?
She did?
페니가 울고 있어?
Is Penny crying?
아니
No.
그래 물론 그렇겠지
No, of course not.
여자들은 남자들의 고통을 즐기니깐
They thrive on our suffering.
친구야, 정말 안됐다
Buddy, I-I'm so sorry.
Is there anything I can do?
내가 도와줄게 있어?
물론이지
만약 내가 다신 여자랑 말이라도 한다면
Yes. If I ever talk about
너가 바보같은 말을 할 때마다
내가 그러는 것처럼
going out with a girl again,
roll your eyes at me
나를 꼬라봐줘
like I do to you
when you say dumb things.
쉘든, 만약에
Sheldon, uh, o-okay,
just because
너가 이렇게 구는게 에이미 때문이라도
you're going through this
with Amy
모든 여자들이 나쁜건 아니야
doesn't mean
that all women are bad.
그러시겠지
Whatever.
너랑 쉘든에 대해서 들었어
Hey, I just heard
괜찮은거야?
about you and Sheldon.
Are you okay?
그렇진 않아
Not really.
와줄 수 있어?
Can you come over?
음, 사실 난 지금 베가스야
Uh, actually I'm in Vegas.
레너드랑 곧 결혼할 것 같아
Leonard and I
are about to get married.
뭐라고?
Hold on.
결혼을 하는데 날 초대도 안한거야?
You're getting married
and you didn't invite me?
그게 충동적으로 해버린거라서
Well, it was kind of
a spur-of-the-moment thing.
와우
Wow.
여기서 부케를 받길 바라야겠네
Hope I can catch
the bouquet from here.
에이미, 그러지마
Amy, don't be like that.
왜 내가 방금 에이미의 이름을 들었지?
Why did I just hear Amy's name?
페니가 지금 걔랑 통화중이거든
Penny's on the phone
with her.
나에 대해선 뭐라고 한거 있어?
Did she say anything about me?
아니야 신경쓰지마
나도 신경 안쓰니깐
Never mind. I don't care.
뭐 너가 신경쓴다면
나한테 말해줘도 되지만
Well, if you care,
you can find out and tell me.
너가 알아낸 것 때문에 충격을 받는다고 해도
난 신경 안쓰겠지만
Just don't be shocked when
you find out that I don't care.
기분 나빠하지마
Okay, will you relax?
특별한건 하나도 없었으니깐
You're not missing
anything special.
저기?
Hey.
에이미가 화났잖아
She's upset.
분명히 멋진 결혼식이 될거야
Look, it's gonna be
a great wedding.
쪼마난 수트 입은 모습 좀 봐
Look at you in
your little suit.
에이미가 화났대?
나 때문에?
Amy's upset? Is it about me?
아니, 나랑 페니가 결혼 때문에
베가스로 온 것 때문인거 같어
No, I think it's because
we're eloping.
너의 결혼이 걔한테 상처를 준거라고?
Your marriage
is causing her pain?
그래, 잘됐네
말을 취소해야겠네
Yeah, great, I take it back.
결혼 계속 해
사랑을 위하여!
Go ahead and do it.
Yay for love!
♪ Our whole universe
was in a hot, dense state ♪
Our whole universe
was in a hot, dense state
♪ Then nearly 14 billion years
ago expansion started... Wait! ♪
Then nearly 14 billion years
ago expansion started... Wait!
♪ The Earth began to cool
The Earth began to cool
♪ The autotrophs began to drool,
Neanderthals developed tools ♪
The autotrophs began to drool,
Neanderthals developed tools
♪ We built the Wall
♪ We built the pyramids ♪
We built the Wall
We built the pyramids
♪ Math, Science, History,
unraveling the mystery ♪
Math, Science, History,
unraveling the mystery
♪ That all started
with a big bang ♪
That all started
with a big bang
♪ Bang! ♪
Bang!
♪ The Big Bang Theory 9x01 ♪
결혼의 운동량
Original Air Date on September 2
The Big Bang Theory 9x01
The Matrimonial Momentum
Original Air Date on September 2
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man
최형준
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man
안녕?
Hello.
Oh!
여기서 뭐하는거야?
What are you doing here?
저번에 우리가 시간이 필요하다고 했었잖아
When last we spoke,
you said you needed time.
겨우 11시간 밖에 안됐잖아
Well, it's only been 11 hours.
반지의 제왕시리즈도 11시간 정도 된단 말야
The Lord of the Rings trilogy
was nearly 11 hours.
나중에 한 번 보여줄게
영원이라는게 뭔지 알게 될거야
I made you watch that,
you said it was an eternity.
쉘든, 때가 되면 내가 말해줄게
Sheldon, when I'm ready to talk,
I'll let you know.
알았어
Very well.
어디 가는 모양이네
You seem to be
headed somewhere.
같이 좀 걸어도 될까?
May I walk with you?
그러든지
Sure.
Boy, I'm glad we're
going out again.
다시 같이 돌아다닐 수 있어서 좋네
소년이여, 다시 함께 할 수 있어 다행이군
Boy, I'm glad we're
going out again.
우리 다시 합친거 아니야
We're not back together.
왜?
Why?
다른 사람이라도 생긴거야?
Is there someone else?
침대를 하루라도 비워두면
Just couldn't wait
for that first notch
안됐던거구만, 그렇지?
on your bedpost, could you?
꼭 알아야겠다면 말해줄게
If you must know,
하워드랑 버나뎃 집에
I'm going to Howard
and Bernadette's
결혼식 보러 가려는거였어
to watch the wedding.
그래서 어떤 남자를 데려가려고 했는데?
And who's this guy
you're taking?
아무도 없어!
There's no guy!
혼자서 결혼식에 가시겠다?
Oh, you're going
to a wedding alone?
안타깝네
That's sad.
혼자는 아니지
I'm not gonna be alone.
내 친구들이 있잖아
I'll be with my friends.
너의 친구들?
Your friends?
내 친구들이겠지
Well, I think you mean
my friends.
그건 그렇고 나는 왜 초대하지 않은거야?
And why wasn't
I invited to this?
아마 우리 둘이 거기에 있으면
Maybe because the two of us
being there
걔네가 불편해져서 그렇겠지
would make them feel awkward.
우린 세상 모두를 불편하게 만들잖아
We make everyone
feel awkward.
그게 우리의 일이라구!
That's our thing!
시간이 좀 걸리네
금방 우리 차례가 올거야
They're running
a little behind.
알았어
Should be pretty soon.
Okay.
배고프면 말해
Hey, if you're hungry,
there's a breakfast buffet
스트립 클럽 옆에 뷔페가 있더라구
at the strip club next door.
고맙지만 내 스크럼블 에그에 반짝거리게 하고 싶지 않아
(스트리퍼는 반짝이를 바르고, egg에 묻히고 싶지 않다)
Thanks, but I don't like glitter
on my scrambled eggs.
스트리퍼들이 만들진 않았겠지만, 뭐 알았어
I don't think the strippers
prepare the meal, but okay.
이런건 내가 생각했던건 결혼식 그림은 아니지만
Look, it-it's not
how I pictured it either,
그래도 우리가 결혼한다는건 여전히 기뻐
but I'm still glad
we're doing it.
-나도
-진짜?
Me, too.
You sure?
물론이지
Yes.
And you promise
차에서 있었던 일들은 괜찮은게 확실하지?
you're okay with
everything from the car?
다시 그 얘기를 하자고?
Oh, my God, would you stop
bringing it up?
너가 맞아, 미안해
You're right.
I'm sorry.
우리는 여생을 과거에 있었던 일들에 대해
We have the rest of our lives
들춰내고 싸우며 살아가겠지
to dredge stuff up from the past
and fight about it.
어떻게 할래?
So what do you think?
빨리 가서 뭐라도 먹고 올까?
Should we run next door
and grab a bite?
우리 차례가 오면 어쩌려구?
What if they call our names?
걱정하지마
진동패드를 주더라구
Oh, don't worry. They gave me
this vibrating coaster.
그렇게 이야기는 계속 됐습니다
Oh, and the fairy tale
continues.
이렇게 해줘서 고마워
Thank you for doing this.
별거 아니야
Our pleasure.
기분은 괜찮아?
You feeling okay?
너무 오랜동안 같이 지냈나봐
We were together for so long,
솔직히 지금 무슨 기분인지도 모르겠어
I honestly don't know
what I'm feeling.
별거 아니야
Well, that's
understandable.
너가 잊고 살았던거지
바로 행복이라고 불리는 거야
You forgot.
It's called "happy."
하워드
Howard.
잘못 말한거 없잖아
I'm not saying
anything bad.
단지 사랑이라는 이름으로 사로잡혀 있었고
Just that she was in love
with her captor
어찌된 일인지 걔의 어둡고 미친 던전에서 탈출 할 수 있게 된거니깐
and somehow managed to escape
from his dark and crazy dungeon.
나도 너가 겪는게 어떤건지 알아
I know
what you're going through.
나도 이전에 헤어진게 꽤 힘들었었거든
My-my last breakup
was pretty tough.
여자 이름이 뭐였는데?
Oh. What was her name?
진짜 이야기라구!
Hey, it's a true story.
더이상 날 괴롭히지마
I don't need the third degree.
(gasps)
쉘든, 뭐하는거야?
For God's sake, Sheldon,
what are you doing?
나도 들어가고 싶지 않아
I didn't want
to come in.
모두를 불편하게 만든다는걸 알거든
I was told it would make
everyone feel uncomfortable.
그러니깐 여기에 그냥 서서
So I'll just stay out here
화장실에 가고 싶지 않은척이나 하고 있을게
and pretend that I don't
have to go to the bathroom.
하워드, 어떻게 좀 해봐
Howard, do something.
기다려봐
I'm on it.
쉘든, 너가 여기 있다고 해서 달라질건 없어
Sheldon, you being here might
not be making things better.
나도 알아
I see.
그게 모두가 날 초대하지 않은 이유야?
And is that why
everybody was invited but me?
얘네가 널 초대하지 않은게 아니야
They didn't invite
everybody but you.
버나뎃이 날 초대한거지
Bernadette invited me,
스튜어트는 여기에 살고 있고
and Stuart lives here.
시나몬 롤 먹을 사람?
(singsongy):
Who wants hot cinnamon rolls?
음악이 들리면 시작되는 겁니다
So, when you hear the music,
that's your cue.
질문이라도?
Any questions?
저희가 지불한 패키지에
Oh, the package
that we paid for
장미 꽃잎이 뿌려지기로 하지 않았나요?
said the aisle was supposed
to be strewn with rose petals.
장미꽃들 어디갔어요!?
Where are the rose petals?!
다 떨어졌어!
WOMAN: We're out!
You know what?
신경쓰지 마세요
It's fine.
화장실에 있는 포푸리는 쓸 수 있어요!
WOMAN: We can use the
potpourri from the bathroom!
저희는 정말 괜찮아요
Really, we're good.
(chuckles)
그냥 결혼이나 할게요
Yup, just want
to get married.
좋아요
Yeah.
Great.
그럼 저 위에서 뵙죠
I'll see you two
up there.
-이렇게 됐네
-그러게
This is it.
I know.
사랑해
I love you.
나도 사랑해
I love you, too.
포푸리라도 가져다 드려요?!
WOMAN: Was that a yes
or no on the potpourri?!
아뇨 괜찮아요!
No, thank you!
We're good!
(string instruments playing
"Bridal Chorus")
라지, 아마도 넌 에이미와 내가 서로에게
Raj, you're probably wondering
아무런 애정도 보여주지 않는지 궁금할테지
why Amy and I aren't showing
any affection to one another.
TOP 10에 들지도 않은 이야기잖아
(별 이야기 아니잖아)
Didn't even crack the top ten.
그럼 이건 알아야겠네
Well, you should know
에이미는 최근에 나랑 헤어졌어
that she recently
broke up with me.
생각할 시간이 필요하다고 했잖아
I said I needed
time to think.
나는 너희가 확실히 해야된다고 생각해
I'm sure you guys
will figure something out.
너도 들었지?
라지가 큰 충격을 받았네
You hear that?
Raj is devastated.
쉔든 쉿!
결혼식이 시작하잖아
Sheldon, shh.
The wedding's starting.
무슨 일인지 알겠다
I see what's happening.
편가르기구만
Sides are forming.
버나뎃이 에이미 팀으로 간다면
난 하워드를 고르겠어
Well, if Bernadette's
on Amy's team, I pick Howard.
난 누구의 편도 들지 않을거야
I'm not taking sides.
알았어
그럼 라지로 고르지
Fine, I guess
I'm stuck with Raj.
진짜로?
Really?
적어도 넌 선택이라도 받았지
At least you
got picked.
나아가기 앞서
Before I go any further,
두 분이 준비한 서약이 있나요?
have either of you
prepared your own vows?
-네
-아니요
Yes.
No.
서약을 준비했어?
You wrote vows?
물론이지
Yeah.
난 아무것도 준비 못했는데
Well, I don't have any.
너가 날 나쁘게 만드는 것 같잖아
You're kind of
making me look bad.
괜찮아
그냥 안하지 뭐
It's okay. I-I don't
have to say them.
아니야, 그냥 해
No, no, no, go ahead.
어차피 내가 아무렇게나 해도 넌 울테니깐
그냥 하자
I'll come up with something
mushy, you'll cry, we got this.
"페니, 우리는 우주가 생긴 이래로
"Penny, we are
made of particles
입자들이 존재하고
"that have existed since the
moment the universe began.
난 이런 원자들이 140억년 동안 시공간을 여행하며
"I like to think
those atoms traveled
우리를 만들어냈다고 생각해
"14 billion years through
time and space to create us,
그렇게 우리는 함께 할 수 있게 되었고
서로의 모든걸 갖게 되었지"
so that we could be together
and make each other whole."
와우
Wow.
페니?
Penny?
맞다, 음, 그러니깐..
Right. Um... okay.
(chuckles)
레너드, 그러니깐, 너가 내 인생에서
유일한 사랑은 아니지만
Leonard, I mean, you're not
only the love of my life.
그러니깐,
넌 내 절친이고
I mean,
you're my best friend, and...
내 영혼의 동반자가 되었지
...you've got a friend in me.
근데 걔가 문제를 일어켰었고
You got troubles.
나도 문제가 생겼고
I got 'em, too.
내가 너한테 해줄 수 있는건 아무것도 없지만
There isn't anything
I wouldn't do for you.
서로 붙어서 같이 계속 하자
We stick together,
and we can see it through,
왜냐면.. 넌 내 영혼의 동반자니깐
'cause... you've got
a friend in me.
토이 스토리에서 나오는 노랫말 아닌가요?
Is that the song
from Toy Story?
그 영화를 좋아하거든요
He loves that movie.
맞아요
(voice breaking):
I do.
정말 아름답다
Aw, that was beautiful.
Yeah.
맞아, 그러니깐 우리 결혼식 같진 않지만
I mean, not like our
wedding beautiful.
당연하지, 우리가 완벽하게 이겼어
No, we totally won.
에이미, 난 이해가 안돼
우리 헤어진거야 아니야?
Amy, I don't understand,
are we broken up or not?
아직 마음의 결정을 못한 것 같은데
It's like you can't
make up your mind.
너가 생각할 틈을 주지 않으니깐 그렇지
It's because you're not
giving me any space to think.
그렇다면 빨리 생각하는게 좋을거야
Well, you should think fast,
왜냐하면 남자는 언제든지 자손을 만들 수 있거든
because men can sire offspring
their entire lives,
하지만 너가 갖고 있는 알들은 유통기한이 있으니깐
but those eggs you're toting
around have a sell-by date.
그거 알아, 쉘든?
너가 점점 쉽게 만들고 있다는걸
You know what, Sheldon,
you've made this really easy.
넌 미성숙하고, 이기적일뿐만 아니라
내 바로 앞에서 날 무시하고 있잖아
You're immature, you're selfish,
you just insulted me to my face.
더이상 생각할 시간은 필요없어
우린 헤어졌으니깐
I don't need any more time
to think. We're broken up.
에이미
Amy...
누가 나 좀 데려다 줄래?
Will someone take me home?
그래 가자,
내가 태워다줄게
Yeah. Come on,
I'll give you a ride.
여러분의 영원한 사랑을 상징합니다
MINISTER:
...symbolizes your eternal love.
저는 이제 당신들이 남편과 아내가 되었음을 선포합니다
I now pronounce you
husband and wife.
우리 결혼했어!
We did it!
너네도 지켜보고 있어서 다행이다!
I'm so glad
you guys could watch!
댓글에 아름다운 결혼식이었다고 달아야겠어
We'll say it was beautiful
in the comment section.
잠깐만 기다려봐
No, no, no. Hang on.
내가 문지방을 들어서 옮겨줄게
I believe I'm supposed to
carry you across the threshold.
할 수 있겠어?
Can you?
쉘든이 티비를 보다가 잠들면
Who do you think
carries Sheldon to bed
침대로 옮겨주는게 누구라고 생각한거야?
when he falls asleep
in front of the TV?
알았어, 한 번 해보자
Okay, let's do it.
(sighs)
(grunts)
(grunting softly)
-괜찮겠어?
-괜찮아
You gonna make it?
I'm okay!
(grunts)
(both chuckle)
잘해냈네!
Nicely done!
고마워
Thank you. (chuckles)
드디어 호프스테터 부인이
Finally, there's
a Mrs. Hofstadter
나한테 실망하지 않게 됐네
who isn't disappointed in me.
글쎄, 아직 밤은 시작도 안했는걸
Well, the night is still young.
(chuckles)
괜찮은거지?
Everything all right?
응, 아마도
Yeah. I guess.
말해봐
Just tell me.
그냥 우리가 키스할 때마다
It's just, when we were kissing,
너랑 다른 여자가 생각나
I couldn't help but picture
you with that other girl.
안돼
Oh, no.
제발
No, come on.
난 이제 영혼의 동반자라구
I have a friend in you.
너도 그렇게 말했어
You said so.
너가 맞아
잊어버리자
You're right.
Just forget it.
(chuckles)
Yeah.
그러니깐, 들어봐
Okay, listen. Uh...
너가 그 일을 야하게 생각하건 아니건
If you're imagining that
it was sexy, it wasn't.
우리 둘 다 취해있었고
걔한테서 재떨이 냄새가 났었어
We-we were both drunk, and
she smelled like an ashtray.
배도 많이 흔들렸었고
내가 걔 이를 하나 부러뜨렸어
The boat was moving a lot,
so I chipped her tooth.
죄책감을 느꼈었어?
Did you feel guilty?
아니, 걘 치과보험을 들어놨었거든
No, she had
dental insurance.
걔랑 키스하고 난 후에 죄책감을 느꼈냐구
Did you feel guilty
after kissing her?
당연히 그 일이 있은 후 바로 죄책감을 느꼈지
Yes. I felt guilty as
soon as it happened.
그앨 볼 때 마다 그랬었어
I feel guilty
every time I see her.
걜 볼 때 마다라는 말은 무슨 의미야?
What do you mean,
every time you see her?
무슨.. 의미일까?
What... do I mean?
난제에 부딪혔군
Boy, that's a toughie.
아직도 걜 보는거야?
You still see her?
뭐, 사적으로는 아니지
Well, no, not socially.
너도 알다시피 일을 할 땐..
But, you know,
just at work.
걔랑 같이 일한다고!?
You work with her?!
(groans)
어떻게 나한테 말을 안한거야!?
How could you not tell me that?!
차에서 말하려고 했는데
너가 말을 막았잖아!
I wanted to tell you in the car,
but you told me to stop talking!
그래서 이게 내 잘못이다?
Oh, okay. So you're saying
this is my fault?
물론 아니지
No, of course not.
이러지 말고,
(stammers) Okay, l-look,
싸우는 대신에
instead of fighting,
불을 좀 어둡게 하고
why don't we dim the lights,
옷 벗고 애를 만드는건 어때?
um, get naked and make a baby?
분위기 좀 살려보려고 한건데
I was trying
to lighten the mood.
쉽지 않네
네 차례야
It's not easy. You try it.
여보세요, 엄마
Hello, Mother.
쉘리! 우리 애기 잘 지내니?
Shelly! How's my baby doing?
그냥 밤마다 하는 기도에서 에이미를 빼도 된다고
I just wanted to let you know
알려드리려고 전화했어요
that you can remove Amy
from your nightly prayers.
걔 머리에 벌집이 떨어지는
Unless you're open
to praying for
기도는 안하셔도 되요
a beehive to fall on her head.
무슨 일이니?
Oh, what's going on?
저랑 헤어졌거든요
She broke up with me.
쉘리야
Oh, Shelly.
전 괜찮아요
No, I'll be okay.
근데 반지는 다시
But I think that I'd like
되돌려 보내야 할 것 같아요
to send the ring back to you.
너무 성급하게 굴진 말거라
Well, let's not be hasty.
정말 완전히 헤어진거니?
Are you sure it's over for good?
이제 전 끝났어요
여자랑 볼 일은 없어요
It's over for me.
I'm done with women.
제가 불량식품을 끊는다고 맹세할 때처럼요
Like when I swore off Pop Rocks.
그 둘다 엄마에게 상처가 됐겠지만요
They both hurt you on purpose.
무슨 일이 있었는지 말해주겠니?
You want to tell me
what happened?
이것도 모두 신의 계획이라고 하실건가요?
Are you going to say
it's all part of God's plan?
좋은 기회가 되겠네
Good chance.
그럼 됐어요
Then no, thank you.
아직 반지는 갖고 있으렴
Well, honey,
don't send it back yet.
네 누이도 결혼했는데
Your sister's married,
and I'm not letting your brother
네 형이 만나는 창녀한텐 주고 싶지 않으니 말이다
give my grandmother's ring
to that whore he's dating.
막달라 마리아도 평판이 나쁜 여자 아닌가요?
Wasn't Mary Magdalene
a woman of ill repute?
네 멍청한 형이 구원을 받았다고 해도
When your idiot brother
redeems mankind,
아무나 만나도 되는 것은 아니란다
he can date whoever he wants.
지금은 상처가 심하겠지만
점점 괜찮아질거야
I know it hurts now,
but it's gonna get better.
맞아
Yeah.
결국 모든건 잘 되기 마련이야
Everything's gonna be okay.
지금은 좀 혼란스러울거야
You've got so
much to offer.
고마워
Thank you.
널 가진 남자는 행복한 사람일거야
Any man would be
lucky to have you.
그럴거야
That's true.
난 그냥 내가 옳은 일을 하길 바랐어
I just hope
I did the right thing.
넌 그렇게 했어
I'm sure you did.
아마 너는 항상 옳은 일을 하려는게 문제일지도 몰라
Maybe that's the problem--
you always do the right thing.
아마도 이제 잘못된 일을 할 때일지도
Maybe it's time to
do the wrong thing.
지금 니가 하는 것처럼?
Like you're doing right now?
물론이지
Exactly.
괜찮은거냐고 여러번 물어봤었잖아
I asked you over and
over if you were okay.
그렇지 않았는데 왜 결혼식은 계속 한거야?
Why would you go through with
the wedding if you weren't?
그게 괜찮은건줄 알았지
나와보니 아닌걸 어떡해
I thought I was okay,
but it turns out I'm not.
난 전적으로 신뢰하고 한거였는데
Okay, listen, I may not
have been entirely faithful,
넌 그렇지 않은 것 같다!
but you,
you are not easy to lift!
와우!
Wow!
결혼하고 나더니
Well, marriage must agree
with you.
완전히 불이 붙었네
Well, you are just glowing.
달아 오른게 아니야
I'm not glowing.
화가 난거지
I'm upset.
어쨌든 잘됐네
Well, whatever it is,
it agrees with you.
똑똑똑, 페니?
Knock, knock,
knock, Penny?
똑똑똑, 페니?
Knock, knock, knock, Penny?
이게 뭐야?
What's this?
레너드가 무슨 일이 있었는지 말해줬어
Leonard told me what happened,
그래서 따뜻한 차를 만들어주려고 왔어
so I took it upon myself
to make you a hot beverage.
정말 친절하네
Oh. That's so sweet of you.
나도 알아
Yeah. I know.
알고보니, 요즘 여자애들에게
Turns out, being sweet
달콤한 것은 더 이상 충분하지 않더라고
isn't enough
to keep a girl these days.
마돈나가 탓이지
I blame Madonna.
너랑 에이미 일은 안됐어
I'm sorry to hear
about you and Amy.
레너드일도 유감이야
Well, I'm sorry
about Leonard.
내가 더 좋은 놈으로 길렀어야 했는데
Thought I raised him
better than that.
여태 일어났던 일은 상관없어
You know, it's bad enough
what happened,
하지만 학교에서 여전히
but then he tried to hide
the fact that he sees her
그 여자애를 보는 사실을 숨기려고 하잖아
all the time
at the university.
걔가 그랬어?
누군데?
He does? Who is it?
맨디라는 이름의 여자애
(scoffs) Some girl named Mandy.
-맨디 차오?
-맞아
Mandy Chao?
Yeah.
그럼 걱정할 필요 없어
Oh, you don't need
to worry about her.
그 여잔 명석하고 매력적이거든
She's brilliant and attractive.
레너드보다 훨씬 잘났거든
She can do way better
than Leonard.
다행이네
That's great.
(clears throat)
잠깐만 있어봐
Wait a minute.
이게 좀 억지같긴 하지만
I know this may
sound farfetched,
난 지금 매물로 나왔잖아
but I'm on the market now.
만약 내가 맨디랑 만난다면
You know, if I dated Mandy,
레너드와 에이미에게 뭔가를 좀 보여줄 수 있을 것 같네
that would teach both
Leonard and Amy a lesson.
그건 말도 안돼
That's ridiculous.
니 말이 맞아
레너드나 만나는 자존감이 낮은 여자는
Oh, you're right.
I could never be with a woman
다신 만나지 않겠어
whose self-esteem was so low
she'd be with Leonard.
난 레너드와 함께거든?
I'm with Leonard.
그렇지, 영원히
Yeah, I know. Forever.
(sighs)
우리한테 이런 일들이 생길거라고 누가 알았겠어?
Who would have believed
these things would happen to us?
그렇지?
Right? (scoffs)
난 실제로 에이미가 그러리라곤 생각도 못했어
I can't believe Amy
actually went through with it.
잠깐만
Hang on.
넌 걔가 나랑 끝낼 줄 알고 있었어?
You knew that she was
going to end it with me?
말려보려고 했어?
Did you try
and stop her?
난 그냥 정말 행복한 일을 하라고 말해줬을 뿐이야
I told her to be true to herself
and do what makes her happy.
걜 행복하게 하는걸 하라고?
Do what makes her happy?
걘 하프도 연주하고
차 할부도 갚았잖아
She plays the harp and
her car is paid for.
그거보다 행복한게 어딨겠어?
How much happier can she be?
걔가 널 나쁜 남자친구라고 생각하는건
Okay, look, it's not my fault
내 잘못이 아니잖아
that she thought
you were a bad boyfriend.
잘 알았어
I see.
저기..
Well...
이만 가봐야겠군
I think I'll be going.
쉘든
Sheldon...
No, no, no, no.
여기서 끝내자
We are done here.
(sighs)
문 좀 열어줄래?
Would you mind
opening the door
그리고 내가 나가면 문 좀 세게 닫아줄래?
and then angrily slamming it
behind me?
알았어
Sure.
고맙네
Thank you.
그리고 아주 세게 닫아
And slam it hard,
난 지금 꽤 열받았거든
because I am pretty steamed.
알았어, 레너드
잘 버티고 있어
All right, Leonard,
hang in there.
내일 얘기하자
Talk to you tomorrow.
무슨 일이래?
걔네 방금 결혼했잖아
What happened?
They just got married.
나도 모르겠어
(sighs)
I don't know.
엉망진창이네
베가스에서 크게 싸웠다나봐
It's a mess.
They had a huge fight in Vegas.
걔네가 헤어질까?
Think they'll break up?
모르겠지만 좋지 않은 상황인 것 같아
I don't know. Sounds pretty bad.
페니가 혼자서 자기 아파트로 가버렸대
Penny's back in her apartment
all by herself.
그렇단 말이지?
Really?
왜 남자가 여자보다 나은지
Would you like to hear
another reason
다른 이유도 들어볼래?
why men are
better than women?
백 개라도 들어보지 뭐
Sure, let's make it
an even hundred.
너는 나랑 키스하지도 않을거고
나한테 사랑한다는 말도 강요하지 않을뿐더러
You would never kiss me
and make me say "I love you"
나랑 헤어지지도 않을거잖아
and then break up with me.
그럴테지
I wouldn't.
왜 그런지 알아?
And you know why?
너는 남자잖아
'Cause you're a man.
성별의 승리자지
The champagne of genders.
내가 남자일지는 몰라도
Well, I may be a man,
이 일들을 망쳐버린건 나인걸
but I think I'm the one
that screwed up on this one.
맞아, 그리고 넌 시인했지
남자처럼
Yeah, well, and you admit it,
like a man.
여자들이 하는 말들은
All you hear
women say is,
"나 샐러드 먹었어"
"I'll just have a salad."
You know?
"내 립글로즈가 어딨지?"
"Where's my lip gloss?"
"내 생각엔 이 물질은 라듐이라고 불러야 할 것 같아"
"I think this element
should be called radium."
마지막껀 퀴리부인이었어
That last one was Madame Curie.
나도 알고 있어
I figured that out.
그거 알아?
그녀는 명예 남자였지
You know what?
She was kind of an honorary man.
과학으로 만든 성기가 있었거든
She had a penis made of science.
내가 너랑 신혼 첫날밤을 보내고 있다는게
믿기지가 않는다
Can't believe I'm spending
my wedding night with you.
진짜로?
Really?
난 그 달리 생각한게 없는데
I never imagined it
any other way.
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man